Guide to the Central African Republic Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Central African Republic collection
1962-2003
MS 1509
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
3.75
(4 boxes)
The collection consists of printed material relating to political, economic, and social conditions in Central African Republic.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred from the African Collection Curator.
Associated Materials
African Collection, MS 605; African Postcard Collection, MS 1575; Pamphlet Collection, MS 1351. Manuscripts and Archives, Yale University Library.
Arrangement
The material in the original accession is arranged chronologically. Additions to the collection may vary in arrangement.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of printed material relating to political, economic, and social conditions in Central African Republic.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Children -- Central African Republic; Women -- Central African Republic; Central African Republic -- Politics and government; Central African Republic -- Description and travel; Central African Republic -- Economic conditions; Central African Republic -- Social conditions; Bokassa, Emperor of the Central African Empire, I, 1921-1996; Front patriotique pour le progrès (Central African Republic)
- Original Accession, 1979-1991, undated
  - Emperor Bokassa I and the Bangui massacre: newspaper clippings, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - General information pamphlets; brochures; booklets, 1979-1982 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Government documents: journals; bulletins; printed material, [1982?] (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Political organizations: journals; printed material; reports, 1987-1991, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Front Patriotique pour le Progrès (FPP): documents; bulletins; printed material, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Women's movement/organizations: printed material, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Additional Material, 1962-1996; Accession 1995-M-142
  - Agence Centrafrique Presse [news bulletin], 1994 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "Agriculteur ouvre les yeux" [Campagne d'Année J. A. C.], 1984- 1985 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - L'Assemblée Nationale de la République Centrafricaine "Guide à l'Usage des Députés", 1993 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - "L'Attitude Scientifique", 1996 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - "Le Conseil Economique et Social", 1962 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - "Conseils pour la Dissertation et le Commentaire Philosophiques" [government publication by Henri Bomba], 1994-1995 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - "Discours Programme de Son Excellence, Monsieur Le Premier Ministre, Chef du Gouvernement", 1994 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - "N'Djamena Hebdo" [Revue Périodique d'Information Générale, no. 13], 1991 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - "Statuts adoptés par l'Assemblée Constitutive du Rassemblement Démocratique Centrafricain", 1987 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Sy, Ismaila, "Les Techniques Electorales", 1996 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - "Traité Thématique d'Histoire et Géographie à l'Usage des Enseignants de la République Centrafricaine", 1990 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - "Vérités Centrafricaines", [1984-?] (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - United Nations Children's Fund (UNICEF) [country kit], undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Additional Material, 1976-1980; Accession 2010-M-100
  - Democratie Nouvelle, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Ita zo ti Kwa: bulletin de liaison des travailleurs du centrafrique, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Additional material, 2003; Accession 2015-M-001
  - Poster, 2003 (Folder 1)